logicmonitor.com 2014-06-25

# Privacy Policy LogicMonitor

(Updated: June 25, 2012)

 **Information Collection & Use**

 This policy describes the privacy practices for LogicMonitor, Inc. (“LogicMonitor,” “us,” “we”) and the ways we collect store, use and protect your personal and non-personal information on our web sites, which link to this Privacy Policy including, without limitation, LogicMonitor.com, Blog.LogicMonitor.com (the “web sites”), along with other sites that may be added to this Policy from time to time.

LogicMonitor offers web-based IT monitoring software solutions (the “services”). For questions or feedback on this policy or our privacy practices, please email us at info@LogicMonitor.com.

 **Uses of Information**

LogicMonitor collects information from individuals who visit the Company’s web sites (“visitors”) and individuals who register to use the services (“customers” or “users”). You do not need to register in order to review the content on this web site as a visitor. Any personal information submitted to us is optional and we use it solely for the purpose for which it is collected or for communicating with you regarding the services. At a minimum we ask for your name, email address, company, and contact phone number so that we may communicate with you.

 **COMMUNICATIONS FROM THE SITE**

 **Special Offers and Updates**

We will occasionally send visitors and users information on our products, educational offers and our newsletter. We will use your name and email address to send these communications to you. Out of respect for your privacy, if you’d prefer not to hear from us you can choose not to receive these types of communications. Please see the “Choice and Opt-out” section below.

 **Services-related Announcements for Users**

We will send you services-related announcements as needed. For instance, as we add software enhancements we may send you an email notification. These emails are necessary for the maintenance of your account with us.

 **Personally Identifiable Information**

Customers use our product to host business data and information related to their business. That business information is considered confidential to our customers. LogicMonitor will not review, share, distribute, or reference any such business data except for the purpose of resolving a problem, providing customer support or to investigate a suspected violation of our business agreement.

We do share personally identifiable information as follows in order to maintain your customer account with us:

All financial and billing information that we collect as provided by you is used solely to check the qualifications of prospective customers and to bill for our services. LogicMonitor uses a third-party credit card processor to assist us in processing customer payments. This processing partner is not permitted to store, retain, or use the personally identifiable information provided, except for the sole purpose of credit card processing.

We may occasionally employ third parties to act on our behalf. Some examples of third party contractors include providing marketing support, analysis and public relations. When we employ such companies they are not permitted to retain, share, store or use personally identifiable information for any other purpose than to complete the contracted assignment.

In some cases we may provide services, or sell product lines jointly with selected business partners.

We DO NOT share personally-identifiable information with third parties for unknown reasons.

 **Legal Disclaimer**

We reserve the right to disclose your personally identifiable information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on us.

 **Choice and Opt-out**

If you no longer wish to receive our newsletter and promotional communications, you may opt-out of receiving them by following the instructions included in each newsletter or communication or by emailing us at info@LogicMonitor.com. You may also contact us by phone at 888.415.6442 or via postal mail: LogicMonitor, Inc., 901 Olive Street, Santa Barbara, CA 93101 to opt-out.

 **Log Files**

As is true of most Web sites, we gather certain non-personally identifiable information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, click stream data and other fields.

We use this information to analyze trends, to administer the site, to track users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole.

 **Cookies**

A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user’s computer for record-keeping purposes. Cookies make web surfing easier for you by saving your preferences while you are at the web site. The use of cookies is an industry standard, and as such, you will find them at most major websites. By showing how and when visitors use the web site, cookies help us see which areas are popular and which are not. Many improvements and updates to the web site are based on such data as total number of visitors and pages viewed. This information is most easily tracked with cookies. We use the information from cookies only to provide services better tailored to our users’ needs.

 **ClickTale**

Some of our sites use ClickTale web analytics service. ClickTale may record mouse clicks, mouse movements, scrolling activity as well as text you type in this website. This site does not use ClickTale to collect any personally identifiable information entered in this website. ClickTale does not track your browsing habits across web sites which do not use ClickTale services. For more information see Privacy Policy for Information Collected by the ClickTale Web Analytics Service. We are using the information collected by ClickTale service to analyze usage of our product to determine future improvements.

You can choose to disable the Service at http://www.clicktale.net/disable.html.

 **Access to Personally Identifiable Information**

If your personally identifiable information changes you may correct or update it by contacting us at info@LogicMonitor.com or by calling 888.415.6442.

 **Public Forums, Referrals and Testimonials**

We may provide public forums like bulletin boards, blogs, or chat rooms on our web sites. These forums are provided as a service to our users to help them exchange ideas, tips, information and techniques related to our services. Any personal information you choose to submit in such a forum may be read, collected, or used by others who visit these forums, and may be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personal information you choose to submit in these forums.

You may also use our referral program to inform friends about our web sites and services. When using the referral program, we request your friend’s name and email address. We will automatically send your friend an invitation to visit our web sites.

We also post a list of users and testimonials on our web sites that may contain information such as the users’ names and titles. We obtain the consent of each user prior to posting any information on such a list or posting testimonials.

 **Security**

The security of your personal information is important to us. We utilize robust security measures to protect customer data from unauthorized access. Sensitive data is encrypted and web site connections are protected using SSL with a minimum of 128-bit symmetric encryption and a 1024-bit authenticated key agreement. Our Web sites are hosted in a secure server environment that uses multi-layer perimeter security including firewalls and other advanced technology to prevent interference or access from outside intruders.

We encourage you to be aware when you leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every Web site that collects personally identifiable information.

 **Business Transitions**

In the event LogicMonitor goes through a business transition, such as a merger, acquisition by another company, or sale of all or a portion of our assets, your personally identifiable information will likely be among the assets transferred.

 **Changes in this Privacy Statement**

We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here and also, as necessary via email.

 **External Links**

Our web sites may contain links to third-party websites. These third party websites maintain their own policies regarding cookies and the collection and use of personal information. We assume no responsibility or liability for the actions of such third parties with respect to their collection or use of your information. We encourage you to read the privacy policies of every website that you visit through a link on our web sites.

 **Contact Us**

If you have any questions or suggestions regarding our privacy policy, please contact us by emailing info@LogicMonitor.com, or by calling 888.415.6442 or via postal mail at: LogicMonitor, Inc., 901 Olive Street, Santa Barbara, CA 93101.
